Preliminary Guide to the Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies Department records, 1930-2003 RG0125
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies Department records
1930-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Dept. of Kinetics and Human Leisure Studies
RG0125
2 Linear Feet
This collection contains annual reports, brochures, questionnaires, applications, news releases, studies programs, teaching loads, and flyers. This material is dated from 1930-2003.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies Department began as a part of the School of Education and Human Development. Until 1994, the Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies Department existed as one of three departments: Education, Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies, and Special Education. The undergraduate degree programs in the Department of Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies were designed for students interested in such fields as athletic coaching and team management, dance, exercise and physical recreation specialists, paramedical field of stress testing, teaching physical education in elementary and secondary schools, tourism and travel, and therapeutic recreation. The department ceased to exist by that name in 1995, and now the same type of degrees may be obtained in the discipline of Exercise Science in the School of Public Health and Health Services. The School of Education and Human Development is now the Graduate School of Education and Human Development.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains annual reports, brochures, questionnaires, applications, news releases, studies programs, teaching loads, and flyers. This material is dated from 1930-2003.
The materials concern the Department of Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies's (HKLS) programs, courses, co-ed recreation, exhibits, dance degree programs, therapeutic recreation technician certificate program, the Institute of Certified Travel Agents, graduate teaching assistants, travel and tourism programs, therapeutic recreation, the International Institute of Tourism Studies, committees, symposiums, seminars, and events. The annual reports are from the Department of Physical Education for Women and Athletes.
Collection Organization
Organized in three series: Department files, Annual reports, and Teaching loads.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Dance; Education; Women; Physical education; Questionnaires; Reports and studies
- Department files, 1975-2003; RG0125 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains flyers, programs, brochures, questionnaires, applications, studies, and news releases. They range in date from 1975 to 2003. The materials concern the Department of Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies's (HKLS) programs, courses, co-ed recreation, exhibits, dance degree programs, therapeutic recreation technician certificate program, the Institute of Certified Travel Agents, graduate teaching assistants, travel and tourism programs, therapeutic recreation, the International Institute of Tourism Studies, committees, symposiums, seminars, and events.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Human Kinetics & Leisure Studies, Department of, 1975-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Human Kinetics & Leisure Studies, Department of Course brochures, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Human Kinetics & Leisure Studies, Department of Special Events, Seminars, 04/28/1975-11/1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Human Kinetics & Leisure Studies, Department of Travel and Tourism Program, 1977-03/12/2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual reports, 1930-1968; RG0125 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains annual reports for athletics and physical education for women. This material is dated from 1930-68.
  Formerly ACC#66
  - Annual Report, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report: Department of Physical Education for Women, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report: Director of Women's Athletics and Physical Education for Women, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    General note
    Includes appendix to annual report
  - Annual Report: Department of Physical Education for Women, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report: Department of Physical Education for Women, 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report to the President: Department of Physical Education for Women, 1930-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Teaching loads, 1960-1970; RG0125 Series 3; .25 Linear feet (Box 2)
  This series contains teaching loads and course descriptions from the departments of Physical Education for Women and Men. Materials range in date from 1960-70.
  - Teaching load: Summary and Course Offerings, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Teaching loads from the Physical Education department, 1960-65. Information includes courses that were taught, names of professors, and correspondence.
  - Teaching load: 1969-1970, Spring-Summer session (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Teaching loads from the Physical Education department, 1969-70. Information includes courses that were taught, names of professors, and correspondence.
- Travel and tourism research publications, 1984-1998; RG0125 Series 4; .5 Linear Feet 1 document box
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains reports relating to tourism research dating from 1984-1998.
  - Technical Assistance for the U.S./Romanian Tourism Program. Final Report, 1984-08-24 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - A Review of Basic Tourism Data Methodologies for the Florida Tourism Industry Marketing Corporation Final Report, by the Institute of Tourism Studies, 1998-06-26 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - An Arabic-language handbook for tour guide training, developed by a partnership between GW and Helwan University in Egypt to train Palestinian and Jordanian tour guides, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)